<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Project Introductions on Deng Peng</title>
    <link>https://deng34.github.io/research/introductions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Project Introductions on Deng Peng</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://deng34.github.io/research/introductions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do We Read Chinese Characters Differently?</title>
      <link>https://deng34.github.io/research/introductions/visual-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deng34.github.io/research/introductions/visual-recognition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does our brain recognize Chinese characters—one of the most complex writing systems in the world? Unlike alphabetic languages where letters combine sequentially, Chinese characters present a fascinating puzzle of intricate spatial arrangements of strokes. Our research explored this mystery by examining the role of strokes in Chinese character recognition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/vr-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chinese stroke neighbors&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;宫 and 官 look similar, only differing by one stroke&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using a technique called masked priming—which involves briefly presenting one stimulus before another to observe the effects on recognition—we investigated a particularly intriguing phenomenon: when readers encounter a Chinese character, how does it affect their recognition of other characters that look nearly identical but differ by just one or two strokes? These &amp;ldquo;stroke neighbors&amp;rdquo; (like 官 and 宫) provide a unique window into the cognitive mechanisms underlying character recognition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Understand That &#34;BOOK&#34; and &#34;book&#34; Are the Same Word at the Early Stage</title>
      <link>https://deng34.github.io/research/introductions/masked-identity-priming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://deng34.github.io/research/introductions/masked-identity-priming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we read English words like &amp;ldquo;BOOK&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo;, we recognize them as the same word almost instantly. This ability to quickly match different forms of the same word is crucial for efficient reading, but how does it work for people learning English as a second language, especially when their native language uses a completely different writing system?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/mip-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;masked priming paradigm&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Structure of a trial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My research examines this question by studying how Japanese students with limited English proficiency process English words. Using a technique called masked identity priming - where words are shown very briefly (for just 50 milliseconds) before being replaced by target words - we found that these learners can quickly access the abstract representations of English words regardless of whether they appear in uppercase or lowercase, much like native English readers do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
